Guide to the Richard Pommer Papers MC.125
New York University Archives
Richard Pommer Papers
1876-1991
1950-1980
New York University Archives
Pommer, Richard
MC.125
22 Linear Feet
The Pommer Papers contain bibliographic sources used in various publications, pertaining in particular to modern German architecture, the evolution of urban apartment housing, and the architecture critic Lewis Mumford.
Arrangement
Files are arranged topically.
The files are grouped into a single series: Papers.
Scope and Contents
These papers contain the working research files of Richard Pommer, who held the Solow Chair of Architecture at the NYU Institute of Fine Arts. The files contain bibliographic sources used in various publications, pertaining in particular to works on the evolution of urban apartment housing, modern German architecture, and architecture critic Lewis Mumford.
Box 17 also contains a small box of bibliographic topics and citations as well as two rolls of microfilm: Creese, Walter L. American Architecture from 1918-1933 with Special Emphasis on European Influence. Harvard University dissertation, 1949; Syracuse University, George Arents Library, assorted magazine articles, photographs and scrapbook entries.
Biography of Richard Pommer
Richard Pommer (1931-1992) was an architectural historian who focused on the Renaissance and Baroque periods. In 1967 he received the Alice Davis Hitchcock Award for his book, 18th Century Architecture in Piedmont. In the 1960s he switched his concentration to modern architecture, particularly that of Germany in the 1920s and 1930s. He was an expert on the architect Ludwig Mies van der Rohe.
Pommer was the Sheldon H. Solow Professor in the History of Architecture at New York University's Institute of Fine Arts from 1988 to 1991. He graduated from Columbia University in 1953 (B.S.) and from NYU's IFA in 1957 (M.A.) and 1961 (Ph.D.). He also taught at Vassar College from 1966-1987.
Access Restrictions
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
This collection is in off-site storage.
Provenance
These materials were transferred to the University Archives by Professor Linda Nochlin of the Institute of Fine Arts.
Apartment houses -- History.; Architecture |x Historiography.; Architecture |x Study and teaching |x History.; Architectural criticism.; Architecture |z Germany |x History |y 20th century.; Reprints.; New York (N.Y.).; Correspondence.; Papers (document genres).; Le Corbusier, 1887-1965; Mies van der Rohe, Ludwig, 1886-1969; New York University. Institute of Fine Arts; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990; Pommer, Richard
- Series I: Papers
  - Art 170, 1982, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058535 1
  - Art 272, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art 271, 1980, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Art 271, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Art 272, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Art 272, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Art 270, 271, 272, 1980, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Art 272, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Art 273, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Art 273, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Art 272, 273, 1986, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Art 272, 273, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ise Gropius Diary (typescript), 1924-1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ise Gropius Diary, inserts (typescript), 1924-1929 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Notes for "Mies and Political Ideology", undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence regarding "Mies and Political Ideology", 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Review of Mies van der Rohe biographies by Franz Schulze and Wolf Tegethoff, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Mies van der Rohe and the Nazi Party, 1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Lothar Kutsch dissertation, "Die NS-Gemeinschaft 'Kraft durch Freude' innerhalb der 'Deutschen Arbeitsfront'" (photocopy), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Annegret Walesch dissertation, "Das Amt 'Schönheit der Arbeit' in der NS-Organisation 'Kraft durch Freude' 1933-1959" (photocopy), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Filler, Martin, "Building and Nothingness," The New York Review of Books, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Friemert, Chup, Schönheit der Arbeit: Produktionsästhetik im Faschismus. (photocopy), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Society of Architectural Historians Conference, Abstracts, Papers, Notes, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Paul Samuel Kruty dissertation, "Frank Lloyd Wright and Midway Gardens", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "'A Necropolis more than a Metropolis:' Ludwig Hilberseimer's Highrise City and Modern City Planning," Richard Pommer, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058536 9
  - Correspondence and travel expenses related to Ludwig Hilberseimer article, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Rough drafts of "'A Necropolis more than a Metropolis:' Ludwig Hilberseimer's Highrise City and Modern City Planning", undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Notes for Ludwig Hilberseimer article, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ludwig Karl Hilberseimer Papers finding aid, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Ludwig Karl Hilberseimer Papers photo inventory and illustrations, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Friedrich Ostendorf, 1926, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photocopied articles and notes for Ludwig Hilberseimer article, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ludwig Hilberseimer buildings, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Der Einzige (photocopies), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Ludwig Hilberseimer (photocopies), 1920-1925 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ludwig Hilberseimer materials from the Bauhaus Archives (photocopies), undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Biographical materials on Ludwig Hilberseimer, 1906-1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Ludwig Hilberseimer: early projects, 1906, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Wohlfahrtsstaat: notes and photocopies, 1927, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ludwig Hilberseimer, 1919-1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Materials on Ludwig Hilberseimer, 1919-1931, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Peter Friedrich, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Non-Hilberseimer, 1924-1934 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ludwig Hilberseimer, Berliner Architektur der 20er Jahre, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Ludwig Hilberseimer, Entfaltung einer Planungsidee, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Grosstadt I, 1914, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Grosstadt Bauwelt, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Ludwig Hilberseimer, "Vom Städtebaulichen problem der Grosstadt" and Grossstadtarchitektur, 1916, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Ludwig Hilberseimer, "Architektur," from Grosstadtbauten, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Gesellschaft und Städtebau", undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Lewis Mumford/Buell articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058537 7
  - Mumford to get, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Buildings outline, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mumford: notes and correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mumford works, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lewis Mumford draft, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mumford lecture - text, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - About Mumford, 1980-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mumford bibliography, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mumford bibliography, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Samson, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Highway"- Mumford article, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Skyline, 1931-1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Skyline, 1949-1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Critique of Humanism, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The Freeman, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - American Mercury - Mumford articles, 1924-1929 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - New Republic - Mumford articles, 1924-1936 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Mumford, various articles, 1917-1930 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mumford - various articles, 1930-1954 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Mumford - Analects and Correspondence, 1970, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Mumford - Books, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - England - 19th century, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Emerson, Greenough, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - America - 19th century - lectures, 1917, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "Organic Expression and Architecture" - Egbert, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Geddes, 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Spengler, 1926-1939 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Utopia/City - Wells, Mumford, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Buell, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Bauer, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Stein, Clarence, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Wright, Henry, 1932-1939, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Other postwar, 1952, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Machine, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Philosophie der Technik, 1920, 1926, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - 1920s literature, history, philosophy, 1921, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Hitchcock, 1927-1948 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Lewis Mumford Collection - Finding Aids, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058539 3
  - Mumford - selected writings, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mumford - finding aids, notes, correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Schuyler, articles, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Other critics, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Frank Lloyd Wright - Modern Architecture, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Wright-Mumford correspondence, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - MOMA Exhibit of Modern Architects - catalog and correspondence, 1932, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - MOMA Archives - notes, correspondence, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Wright-Hitchcock correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Philip Johnson correspondence with Frank Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bibliography about Germany A-M, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bibliography about Germany N-Z, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - New York State Mental Hospital Construction, 1967-1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058540 1
  - Bronx State School, 1967, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Kings County State School Schematic Design, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bronx Developmental Center, 1976-1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Schematic plans (untitled), undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - New York State Urban Development - Twin Parks/Sunnyside Projects, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bronx Developmental Center: notes and schematics, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bronx Developmental Center: notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Bronx Developmental Center: prospectus, fact sheet, and correspondence, 1969-1982 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Paul Rudolph interview notes, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Notes on other Paul Rudolph buildings, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Yale Art and Architecture Building: notes, correspondence, and draft of "The Art and Architecture Building at Yale, Reconsidered", 1971-1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Yale Daily News: notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Paul Rudolph bibliography, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Development of New Haven: notes and bibliography, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Notes on Yale University and A. Whitney Griswold, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Notes on Vincent Scully, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Notes on Paul Rudolph, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Yale Art and Architecture Building: notes and articles, 1963-1974 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Yale Art and Architecture Building: schematic drawings, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Yale Art and Architecture Building: notes and articles; copy of "the Art and Architecture Building at Yale, Once Again," by Richard Pommer, 1935-1937, 1972-1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Paul Rudolph: articles and notes, 1954-1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Notes on Paul Rudolph, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Research Notes on the Yale Art and Architecture Building, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Studio apartment housing: correspondence, notes, and articles, 1912, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - "High Rise Living," by Richard Pommer, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - English apartments: notes and correspondence, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Vienna apartments: notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - French apartments: notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Albert Hall Mansions: notes, schematic prints and negatives, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - "Parisian Flats" lecture, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Lecture on New York apartment housing, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - "High Rise Living": draft, notes, and correspondence, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Apartments: notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Hotels: notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Notes on New York City architecture, 1920s and 1930s, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - American Dwelling Design Project, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058541 9
  - Hubert - Notes, Photos, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Richard Morris Hunt, 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Crowninshield House/Richardson - Blueprints, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hardenbergh/Dakota Stable, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - History of Apartment Buildings - Drafts, bibliographies, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous - Minor Apartments, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1920s Apartments - notes, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Literary - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - NYC Apartment Houses - Flagg, etc., undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Apartment Houses - New York Public Library, N-YHS Materials, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Apartment Houses - Notes, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - New York City Apartment Houses - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "Recent Literature on Housing as Architecture" - Pommer, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Columbia University "Housing and Urban Form", 1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "The Architecture of Urban Housing in the United States in the early 1930s" - draft of Pommer, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "The Architecture of Urban Housing in the United States in the early 1930s" - Pommer, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Committee for the Preservation of Architectual Records, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Anthony Jackson - A Place Called Home - Notes Housing Complexes - Schematic Photos and Negatives, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Pommer "Architecture of Urban Housing" article - correspondence, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Avery - notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - "Recent Literature on Housing as Architecture" - Pommer, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Cornell Library - notes, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Plan Units for Low-Rent Housing- Articles, Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Plan Units-Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Questions and Ideas - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Sociology and Architecture - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Housing for the Elderly - notes, bibliography, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - N.A.H.O. - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - New York City Tenement Housing - Pre-WWI, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Stern, Robert - "With Rhetoric: The New York Apartment House"-, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Garden City - notes, photos, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - World War I Architecture - notes, articles, finding aids, 1960, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Coverage - notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Government archives - notes, finding aids, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Public Works Administration - notes, memoranda, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Housing 1920s and 1930s - Notes, Articles, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Carl Mackley Houses - correspondence, 1972-1978 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - United States Housing Authority - Strauss Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - NY City Housing Authority - Notes, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Housing To Do, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Housing - Notes, periodicals, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Potter, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Williamsburg Houses - Notes, Schematic Drawings, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Red Hook, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Harlem River Houses - notes, blueprints, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - New York City Housing, 1920-1936, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Eugene Klaber/FHA, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Howe and Lescaze, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Chrystie/Forsyth Housing Development, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Queensbridge, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Farmers Home Administration, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058542 7
  - Division of Defense Housing, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Oscar Stonorov - speeches, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stonorov-Cole materials, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Alfred Kastner, 1972-1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Carl Mackley - notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Oscar Stonorov - notes, biography, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Oscar Stonorov - correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Laramie - notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Laramie - projects, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Stonorov and Haws Architects, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Carl Mackley Houses/Juniata Park Housing Corporation, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Andrew Thomas, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Camden Labor Housing Conference, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - John W. Edelman, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Philadelphia Housing Association, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Cedar Central Project - photos, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Lakeview Terrace: Architecture as Housing" by Helen Harrison, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Lakeview Terrace - blueprints, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Weinberg, Teare, Herman Architects, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Wallace Teare, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Central/Scovill Slum Project, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Walter McCornack - publications, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Ernest Bohn, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - "The Development of Public Housing in Cleveland"-Donna Ferguson, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Carl Feiss, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Cleveland - notes, bibliographies, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Adam, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Emilio Ambasz, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Arts and Crafts, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Austria, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Alvar Aalto, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - David Craven, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Raimund Abraham, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Diana Agrest/Marie Gandelsonas, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Marcel Breuer, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Étienne-Louis Boulée, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Butterfeld, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Behne, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - H. P. Berlage, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Walter Curt Behrendt, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Anatole de Baudot, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Belgium, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Bötticher, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Peter Behrens, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Peter Behrens, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Peter Behrens - Tall Buildings, undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - H. P. Berlage, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Catalonia, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058543 5
  - Francesca - Le Corbusier, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Le Corbusier, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Le Corbusier, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Corbusier, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Le Corbusier - 370, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Archive Notes - Esprit Nouveau, SDN, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Le Corbusier - Furniture, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Le Corbusier and De Stijl, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Le Corbusier - educators, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Le Corbusier - Purism, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Le Corbusier - La Chaux-de-Fonds, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Brasilia, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Le Corbusier - Chandigarh, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Le Corbusier - Urbanism, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Le Corbusier - "Deastin de Paris", undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Le Corbusier - Rudolph, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Le Corbusier, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Cubism, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - "Dutch Architecture Between the Wars"-conference, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Deconstuctivist Architecture, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Design, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Darmstadt, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Pommer draft from "Dutch Architecture between the Wars"-colloquium, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - 18th Century England, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - 19th and 20th Century England, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Eiffel, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - August Endell, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Peter Eisenman, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Josef Frank, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Theodor Fischer, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - France, 1920s, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Buckminster Fuller, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - France - 18th Century, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Peter Eisenman, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - France - 19th Century, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Form, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Futurism, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Roger Ferri, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Finland, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Tony Garnier, undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - 18th Century Gardens, undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Charles Garnier, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Gaudi, undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Guadet, undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Getty, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Peter Behrens, undated (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Hector Guimard, undated (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Greek Revival, undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Gropius, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058544 3
  - Bauhaus - Weimar, 1976, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Bauhaus - Dessau, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Märzgefallen, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Gropius, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Gropius - Bauhaus, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Nerdinger, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Graves, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Graves, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Graves, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Graves - Schematic Design Slides, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - John Hejduk, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Holabird, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Victor Horta, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Hegel, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Hoffman, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Holland, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Hübsch, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Isosaki, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Italians, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Pommer - International Style presentation, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Louis I. Kahn - housing, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Jourdain, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Philip Johnson, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Wassily Kandinsky, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Pommer lecture: "Kahn, Mies and the New Museum of Art," Duke University, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - William H. Jordy, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Metabolists, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Thomas Jefferson, undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - De Klerk, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Owen Jones, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Louis I. Kahn, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Adolf Loos, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Edwin Lutyens, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Claude-Nicolas Ledoux, undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Left, undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - William Lescaze, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Carlo Lodoli, 1964-1976 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - C. R. Mackintosh, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Mendelsohn, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Charles W. Moore, undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - William Morris, 1976-1990 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Richard Meier - Westbeth, 1970-1974 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Hermann Muthesius, undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - New York Skyscrapers, undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Friedrich Naumann, undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - 19th Century - General, undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - 19th Century Theory of Design, undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - New York Articles, 1902, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Nietzsche - architecture, undated (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Buell Center - correspondence, minutes, 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058545 0
  - Books - Library slips, review of "Architectura Domestica in Gran Bretagna 1890-1939," bibliography, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Committees, correspondence, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Courses - correspondence, descriptions, 1988-1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)